welcome back
today we are going to do some progress in the Luv tier
namely we haven't done the new circuits yet
and the first thing we have to do to unlock those
is play fetch with the quest book
and that was a breeze
however
the second round starts to be more complicated
the first part of the second round is located
on the moon of a planet of another solar system
but it was nothing harder than getting there
and processing a new ore
the second step requires to find some stuff
that we already managed to get a long time ago
then we have to do some simple processing steps and it's done
for the last fetch quest
we have to change the acid we use to process rare earths
however
while that was enough for this fetch quest
it was not enough for the next step with the size we will want it to be
so we also added a new
prioritized way of processing raw lead ores
the next quests
requires to mix together all the stuff we fetched so far
it's nice to know that we didn't fetch all of that stuff for nothing
the issue is that
the last step of that stuff
has only a chance of succeeding
so if we do not want our AE2 system to get stuck
due to the expected stuff that failed in the process
we shall make a pattern with more inputs than the required ones
finally
when we try to craft that over crafted item
we find ourselves presented with a huge list of ingredients
luckily
our EBF stocked up quite some extra dusts
that we can compact manually
and now we can complete the quest
and all the extra items we have produced in the meantime
will be useful later on
and everything we did so far
was just preparing the tools and materials
for the real circuitry industry
the circuits we are going to do today
are part of the crystal processor series
which starts from emerald crystals
however
making those with emeralds is quite expensive
and has low success chances
the better way is with raw crystal chip parts
but those parts are made with the crystal we need
so we go with the Emerald Way
and here you can see our first failed attempt
we keep trying until we get a successful one
now that we have won the crystal lottery
we want to use that one crystal to craft a pile more
to do so
we have to make a loop where we smash crystals
and then make the fragments grow back by using europium
we could do that passively
but since we are going to craft europium on demand
we also make a pattern for crystal on demand
we will input europium for two crystals in the loop
so that one crystal will be outputed
and one reused to make more crystals
there is going to be some extras
but that's a feature not a bug
and once we set up the two looping machines
we just have to input our only crystal
and some europium to fill up the machines
behold
the legendary mythical secret technique of the crystal multiplication
however
to use those crystals as processors
we first have to cook them with some extra crystals
since we can use both Emerald or olivine
and we can't make up our mind on which one to use
we do a custom pattern that does both at the same time
once our crystals are cooked
we shoot them with lasers
to get some chips which we can now use to finally have our first crystal processor
and here something started to feel weird
for some reason
the cost of that circuit
seems to be 6 times higher than expected
and the reason for that is that
we are probably supposed to use a dedicated circuit assembling line
to craft those circuits
but to use that
we also need a circuit imprint
which has to be made out of the circuit we want to make
so we start by making a pattern for a circuit in the expensive way
but we do not automate that
we will have the ingredients dropped in a chest
so that we will use the expensive way only one time manually
once the ingredients are ready
we craft our first crystal processor to use as a sample
all we have to do to turn it into an imprint
is slice it and then add the stuff we fetched earlier on
now that we have the imprint
required to make circuits in the not as expensive way
we only need an assembly line where to place it
and after some quick crafting
there we have it
all we have to do is place the imprint
and then start making tons of circuits
and then something happened
the imprint made it so that this circuit line
will only be able to craft this specific processor from now on
even if we break it
there is no way of changing recipe
which means we are going to need a lot of those machines
at least one for each recipe
also like the normal assembly line
this one wants stuff in the correct place too
but since it will only craft one single recipe for its whole life
we can just use a filter system to ensure the ingredients go in the correct slot
and now we can slowly craft our first batch of circuits
as usual
they come in four clustering levels
and we use the first two processors to make a processor assembly in the expensive way
then we slice it
to make an imprint for those clustered circuits
and we bind forever the imprint to our 2nd Circuit assembling line
then we realize that
at some point
we will want this setup to work faster than conduits can handle
so we instead switch to an AE2 sub network
which has virtually infinite throughput
using stocking inputs buses
which will allow the assembler to directly take millions of items at once from AE2
that speed will be reached
thanks to the perfect overclocks
that will quadruple the machine speed every tier
for now we go slow
next we prepare everything
for crafting the last two clusters of crystal processors
and with that we have about finished the Luv tier
on a side note
we can also use the new machinery
to make way cheaper HV circuits
and we can quickly update all of our patterns
by just changing the way we make the generic HV circuit
that is being used by all the patterns
also
since all of our CPUs are waiting for the slow 4 circuit assemblers
we can make one more circuit assembling line in circuit assembler mode
for generic simple circuits
the trick here is to have an advanced stocking input bus
with auto pull enabled
that will turn the whole connected ae2 storage into an input bus for that machine
and with that
we are now making in five seconds the circuits
that were taking 80 seconds and a clean room
with that
I think we can move to the ZPM tier
where we already rushed some things that were required for our reactor build
and here instead of playing fetch
we play guess the item with some riddles
since I'm not good at riddles
whose solutions are items I don't have access to
we go with the glutton way
hopefully the ingredients in our farmhouse
that hasn't been checked for 9 episodes didn't go bad
we quickly cook some of the food that this hardworking dude wants
but then we realize that we do not have any lime for his dessert
since he is also picky
I guess
the lesson here is not to give candy to strangers
they might not like the flavor you have at your disposal
going back to our new quest page
I think we can finally get closer to the midgame
with this cool looking block quest
and since those blocks require a ZPM assembler in a clean room
we have to either relocate a ZPM assembler
in a processing array or in a clean room
but we will probably want to get a new one to speed up things
and since we are low on europium
we quickly build a fusion reactor that AE2 will manage
but you should always do more machines than required
and with that
we have our ZPM assembler
that we shall place in a clean room
and now we can start working on crafting those cool looking blocks
once we have made some of each one
we have to choose what machine we shall build with those
and I think we shall start from the active transformer
however
it looks that somehow we missed the monazite for crafting it
to find out how and why
we can check the crafting tree
and follow the branch with the missing ingredient
and it turns out
we are still using monazite for making helium
as a quick fix
we relocate a miner on a nice beach
that miner is of the highest tier
and can mine an area of 300 by 300 blocks
exactly the range of our or prospector
making it so that the prospector shows exactly what we will dig
and upgrading our miners broke the transceiver cover
once we replace it
we can see again our stats
one other source of helium we can use
is from a multi block plasma turbine
running on helium plasma
and now that we have crafted our new transformer
we can start fixing all of the spaghetti under our base
we can now have one single high power cable
being spread by the transformer
into many lower power cables
and thus we spend some time rewiring our base
the next thing we can craft with the cool looking blocks
is a data bank
this one is a multi block
that can take many data hatches
enough to contain all of the researched recipes we have done so far
then using optical fiber cables
it will spread the data to many assembly lines
that way
instead of having a limit of 17 recipes for each assembly line
and having to research an item once for every assembly line
we can do everything on every assembly line
and from the AE2 side
instead of crafting copies of the same pattern for each assembly line
we can use a peer to peer interface
all the interface we link to the first one
will share the same recipes
thus
we can now make a lot of different items
simultaneously in many assembly lines
and with that
I think we can move on with the progression
after completing the superconductor quest
usually
we would expect to unlock the Energy Hatch quest
however nowadays
it looks like it is being gated by something new
and the issue seems to be
with the Nano Power integrated circuit
to work its wafer
we need some flocculated water
to flocculate water
we have to not get distracted by the cool looking UI
and to get a flocculation purification unit
and I think we can all see where this is going
that thing is probably going to need its dedicated episode
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要推进一下 LuV 的进度
新电路都还没做呢
要做的第一件事
便是跟着任务书解锁它们
这可再轻松不过
然而
第二轮开始变得复杂
要达成的第一步
位于另一个太阳系行星的卫星上（罗斯128ba）
不过最大的难点也只是到达那儿
并加工新矿石
第二步需要找到一些东西
不过很久以前我们就已经获得了
然后做一些简单的处理步骤就搞定了
而最后一个任务
必须改变用来处理稀土的酸
不过
虽然已经获得了任务要求的量
但对我们要达到的规模来说还远远不够
所以我们还添加了一个新的
铅粉碎矿的优先处理产线
下一个任务
需要把目前所有的原料合在一起
很高兴知道我们的努力并没有白费
问题是
那东西的最后一步
是一个概率配方
因为此配方很可能在处理中失败
所以如果不想让 AE 卡住
我们需要一个输入比所需量大的样板
最后
当我们试图制作过量的物品时
却发现缺乏了大量的碲粉
幸运地
我们的高炉中存储了大量的副产粉尘
可以手动压缩它们
现在我们可以完成任务了
我们在任务中制作的东西
以后都会有用的
不过迄今为止所做的一切
都只是在准备阶段
还未开始真正制作
我们今天要做的电路
是晶体处理器系列的一部分
从使用绿宝石开始
然而
用绿宝石太贵了
而且成功概率也低
更好的方法是用晶体芯片碎片来循环
但它们又需要晶体芯片原料
所以我们先用绿宝石做
你可以看到第一次的失败尝试
保持努力，直到成功获得一个
既然我们中了水晶彩票
我们想用那一块晶体芯片原料复制出一堆
要这样做
我们必须先将其打碎
再通过铕让其完成一次循环生长
这可以做个被动产线
但既然我们要按需生产铕
我们便按需制作晶体样板
我们将为循环中的两个晶体输入铕
这样便会输出一个晶体芯片原料
另一个则被重复使用以制造更多晶体
这会有些额外的产物
但那是特性而不是 BUG
一旦安装好了两台循环机器
我们只需要输入唯一的晶体
和一些铕来填满机器
敬请见证
传说中的晶体倍增神秘科技
然而
要使用这些晶体作为处理器
我们必须用一些额外的水晶来处理它们
不过绿宝石和橄榄石都在考虑范围内
不太好决定用哪一个
我们做了一个同时发配两类晶体的样板
一旦晶体处理完毕
再通过激光蚀刻
便获得能用来制作晶体处理器的芯片
这配方有点怪
出于某种原因
电路板的成本
似乎比预期高6倍
原因是
我们应当使用电路装配线
来制作那些电路板
而要使用它
我们还需要一个压印电路
它必须由我们想要制作的电路制成
所以我们首先以昂贵的方式为电路制作压印电路
但我们不自动化这个步骤
而是把原料放进箱子里
这样就只需要用一次这个高价配方了
一旦材料准备好
我们制作了第一个晶体处理器用作样品
把它变成压印电路的步骤是
将其切片，然后加上我们之前拿到的东西
现在我们有了压印电路
可以用廉价的方式制作电路板了
我们就差一条电路装配线了
经过快速制作
它来喽
我们把压印电路放进去
然后开始制作成吨的电路板
但有些事需要注意
这条电路装配线因为压印电路
已经只能制作这一种电路板了
即使拆除主方块
也不会改变其配方
这意味着我们将大量需要这种机器
每个配方至少一台
像普通的装配线一样
它也需要将物品输入正确的仓室
但是因为它一生只能制作一个配方
我们可以使用过滤系统来确保物至其位
现在我们可以慢慢制作第一批电路了
像往常一样
它们有四个级别
我们用前两个晶体处理器以昂贵的方式做一个集群
然后切片
为这电路板做出压印电路
将它绑定到第二条电路装配线上
然后我们意识到
在之后
我们希望这个产线比管道能处理的更快
所以我们改为使用 AE 子网
它几乎具有无限的吞吐量
使用存储输入总线
允许装配线一次性从 AE 中抽取数以万计的物品
这样的速度是可能的
多亏了无损超频
每升压一次机器速度便翻四倍
现在它还是比较慢
接下来我们准备好一切
制作晶体处理器系列最后两个电路板
这样我们就快完成了 LuV 的任务了
顺便说一句
我们也可以使用新机器
制造更便宜的 HV 电路
只需要改变制作任意 HV 电路板的配方
就能将所有使用 HV 电路板的样板轻松更新
而且
因为所有的 CPU 都在等待
那慢吞吞的 4 并行电路组装机
我们可以做一条电路组装机模式的电路装配线
来普适地做简单电路
这里的诀窍是用一个进阶存储输入总线
启用自动拉取
这将把整个连接的 AE 存储
变成这台机器的输入总线
有了这个
我们便可以在五秒内完成制作
之前需要在超净间内等待 80 秒的电路
有了那个
我想我们进入 ZPM 电压了
我们已经仓促完成了建造反应堆所需的任务
我们在这不是跟着任务收集物品
而是做个猜谜游戏
由于我不擅长猜谜语
而谜底是我们无法获取的东西
我们先满足出题人的食欲
希望我们农舍里的配料
在九集时间流逝下没有变质
我们很快做出这个勤劳的家伙想要的一些食物
但很快发现我们没有他想要的酸橙
既然他也很挑剔
我猜
今天的教训是不要给陌生人糖果
他们可能不喜欢你的口味
返回新的任务页面
我想我们已经进入游戏中期了
有了这些看上去很酷的任务
由于这些材料需要超净间环境的 ZPM 组装机处理
我们得重新在处理阵列或者超净间中
做一个 ZPM 组装机
但我们可能需要一个新玩意来提高效率
不过我们的铕存量太少
我们快速建造一个由 AE 管理的聚变反应堆
多堆点机器总是好的
有了这个
我们便获得了ZPM组装机
将其放置在超净间中
现在便可以考虑制作那些很酷的方块了
一旦完成一些方块的制作
我们就要决定要拿它们做什么机器了
我认为有源变压器是第一位的
然而
看起来我们缺少独居石来制作它
要知道为什么
我们可以检查合成树
并跟随缺失成分的分支
结果证明
我们仍在使用独居石制造氦气
作为快速解决方案
我们在一个风景宜人的海滩上拍下采矿厂
这个 IV 级采矿场
可以开采 300x300 的方块
而这正是我们探矿仪的范围
这样探矿仪就能准确地看到我们要挖的东西
升级采矿场导致传感器卡片坏了
将其更换
我们便可以再看到数据
我们可以用的另一种氦源
来自多方块等离子涡轮机
它靠氦等离子体运行
现在我们已经制作好了新变压器
可以开始修整基地下的凌乱电线了
现在可以用一根大功率电缆
通过有源变压器
输出多根低功率电线
因此，我们花了一些时间重新给基地布线
接下来用这些好看方块可以做的结构
是一个数据库
它是一个多方块结构
可以存储多种闪存
足以包含我们迄今为止所做的所有研究
然后使用光纤
它可以将闪存数据传输给多个装配线
用这个方式
装配线不再只能做 17 个配方
也不需要每个装配线都研究一次
任意一条装配线都可以随意制作物品了
对于 AE
不需要每个装配线都写一样的配方
我们可以使用 p2p 接口
所有连接到第一个 p2p 接口的接口
都会共享相同的样板
因此
在多个装配线下
我们可以同时制作多个物品
有了这个
我想我们可以推进度
完成超导任务后
通常
我们希望可以解锁能源仓任务
然而如今
它看起来像是被新的东西锁住了
似乎是
纳米功率 IC 晶圆的问题
为了获得它
我们需要一些絮凝水
使水絮凝
我们不能被酷炫的 UI 分散注意力
想获得絮凝净化单元
我想我们都可以看到这将走向何方
它需要专门的一集
拜拜
（零点压，Zero Point Module, ZPM）
（ p2p 通道 — ME 二合一接口）
（最坐牢的净化水线）